[Music]
[音乐]
yeah thanks can you hear me okay thanks
是的，谢谢你能听到我好吗，谢谢
for the introduction
为介绍
mark did a good job in pronouncing my
马克在宣告我的发音方面做得很好
name I didn't think he could do it but
我没想到他能做到
he did yes I'm going to talk about clean
他是的，我要谈论清洁
architecture today little some words
今天的建筑有点话
about me I'm a software engineer at
关于我，我是
adesso in Germany were software
德国的adesso是软件
consultancy so I've been in the
顾问，所以我去过
consulting business for the last 12
最近十二年的咨询业务
years doing java mainly doing a little
年做java主要做一点
bit of open-source and I just took this
一点开源，我就用了
this screenshot this morning to have it
今天早上有这张截图
to have it up to date I just looked here
让它保持最新状态我只是看这里
there's something wrong here in April
四月这里出事了
I think github had an error or something
我认为github有错误或其他问题
like that actually if I think about it
如果我考虑一下的话
that's the time my current project
那是我目前的项目时间
started into the hot phase of roll out
开始进入热销阶​​段
and well didn't have time for open
而且没有时间开放
source then okay so that's enough about
来源，然后好，这样就足够了
me I'm going to talk about clean
我我要谈论清洁
architecture architecture in general are
一般而言，架构
going to motivate what clean
要激励什么干净
architecture is about and hexagonal
建筑大约是六角形
architecture as an instance of clean
建筑作为清洁的实例
architecture but first I'm going to talk
建筑，但首先我要谈
about the layered architecture style
关于分层的建筑风格
we're all so fond of who has done
我们都很喜欢谁做了
layered architecture in a project hands
项目手中的分层体系结构
up
上
yeah that's pretty much everyone I guess
是的，我猜几乎每个人
that much obviously I'm showing this
显然我正在展示这个
slide only to set up layered
仅滑动以设置分层
architecture to compare to another
与其他建筑进行比较
architecture style that it's much better
更好的建筑风格
so have your Rotten Tomatoes handy and
所以请随身携带烂番茄
throw them at me when I'm going to bash
我要扑的时候把它们扔给我
on layered architecture but first of all
在分层架构上，但首先
before we talk about the pros and cons
在我们讨论利弊之前
of different architecture styles let's
不同的建筑风格让我们
talk about what architecture actually is
谈论什么是架构
so why do we actually bother with
那么为什么我们实际上要打扰
architecture at all why aren't we just
根本不是我们的建筑
coding away and put it into production
编码并投入生产
and they do it work all it works on my
他们做到了，所有的工作都对我有效
machine so it should work there
机器，所以它应该在那里工作
what is architecture about what are the
什么是架构
goals of architecture anyone what why
任何人的建筑目标为何
are we doing why are we thinking about
我们在做什么为什么我们在考虑
architecture just throw it at me
建筑就把它扔给我
what was that readability okay usability
那可读性还可以的可用性是什么
well actually any ility you can find
实际上，您可以找到的任何灵活性
right so yeah you're completely right
对，是的，你是完全正确的
some people think that architecture is
有些人认为建筑是
about making making it work making the
关于使它工作
software work obviously we're building
我们正在构建的软件显然
as we're thinking about when we're doing
当我们在思考何时做
architecture it shouldn't be in the way
架构不应该成为障碍
of making the software we're building
制作我们正在构建的软件
work so our architecture should enable
工作，所以我们的架构应该启用
the software to actually implement the
实际实施的软件
requirements that were given to us but
给我们的要求，但是
there is software out there that has a
那里有一个软件
an awful architecture but it's still
糟糕的架构，但仍然
working best what 101 good example is
最有效的101个很好的例子是
our own ERP system at adesso we bought
我们在阿德索购买了自己的ERP系统
it we didn't build it ourselves so
它不是我们自己建造的
nothing we didn't do anything wrong
没有，我们没有做错任何事情
except to buy it but it's it's it has an
除了买它，但是它有一个
awful architecture when you use it as an
糟糕的架构，当您将其用作
software engineer to track your time and
软件工程师跟踪您的时间并
track invoices and stuff like that you
跟踪发票和类似您的东西
just feel that it's a bad architecture
只是觉得这是一个糟糕的架构
underneath you have the same forms in
在你下面有相同的形式
every on every page and you have a very
每个页面上的每个页面都有一个非常
bad UX experience so but but we it's
用户体验不好，所以，但是我们
working we're we're profitable we are
工作，我们就盈利，我们就
creating invoices through that system
通过该系统创建发票
the invoices are getting paid even and
发票甚至被支付
it works
有用
but it only works because we have to use
但这只能工作，因为我们必须使用
it so there is software out there that
所以那里有软件
has a bad architecture and it's it's
架构不好，就是这样
working nonetheless so this is not the
尽管如此，所以这不是
main goal of architecture you were right
建筑的主要目标是正确的
with with all the abilities this is that
具有所有能力的是
the quality attributes the quality
质量决定了质量
requirements to our architecture that's
对我们架构的要求
that's what architecture is about it's
这就是架构的意义所在
about facilitating the whole development
关于促进整体发展
experience facilitating development
促进发展的经验
facilitating deployment to production or
促进部署到生产或
even to test environments
甚至测试环境
it's about facilitating maintenance
是为了方便维护
because maintenance is more expensive
因为维护更昂贵
than actually building the software
比实际构建软件
initially and with these le T's we're
最初，有了这些T，我们
trying to achieve with architecture
试图用建筑来实现
we're trying to keep the software soft
我们正在努力使软件保持软性
so these three phrases down here are
所以这三个词是
quotes from Robert Martin's book clean
罗伯特·马丁（Robert Martin）干净书中的名言
architecture so we want to keep the
建筑，所以我们要保持
software soft because software the the
软件软，因为软件
meaning of software is that it's
软件的含义是
flexible that we can we can we can push
灵活，我们可以，我们可以推动
it we can poke at it and it changes
我们可以戳它，它会改变
compared to hardware for which you
与您所使用的硬件相比
actually have to break things and
实际上必须打破事物，
reassemble them we want to keep
重新组装它们，我们要保留
frameworks at arm's length so we don't
框架相距不远，所以我们不
want to build upon the features of a
想要建立在
framework we don't want to bind to the
我们不想绑定到的框架
framework too much because if the
框架太多，因为如果
framework changes we have to change our
框架变更我们必须改变我们的
business co2 and we want to avoid that
商业二氧化碳，我们希望避免这种情况
and we want to keep options open we want
我们想要保持选项打开
to have we want to make decisions at the
让我们想在
lightest possible moment and keep our
最轻的时刻，并保持我们
options open until then so the goal the
选项打开，直到那时目标
the ultimate goal of software
软件的最终目标
architecture is to minimize the lifetime
体系结构是为了最大限度地减少寿命
cost of the software a lifetime cost
软件成本终生成本
means the development cost of course but
当然意味着开发成本，但是
it also means the maintenance cost
这也意味着维护成本
afterwards because that's I don't know
之后，因为那是我不知道
the numbers but
数字但是
maintenance is factor of I don't know
维修是我不知道的因素
how much more expensive than actually
比实际贵多少
building it so now we know that the goal
建立它，所以现在我们知道目标
of software architecture is to minimize
软件体系结构的目的是最大程度地减少
cost to keep options open and everything
保持期权开放及一切所需的成本
I introduced the layer architecture and
我介绍了层架构，
the start so what's wrong with layers
开始，所以层怎么了
first of all it before I start bashing
首先，在我开始扑扑之前
the layered architecture and get thrown
分层架构并被抛出
at with Rotten Tomatoes a little
与烂番茄一起
disclaimer layer layers are a solid
免责声明层是坚实的
architecture pattern we there's a reason
建筑模式，我们有一个理由
why we all do it and if you do it right
为什么我们都这样做，如果您做对了
then it's a perfect perfect decision to
那是一个完美的完美决定
do a layered architecture I'm doing this
做一个分层的架构
myself in my current project but before
我自己在当前项目中，但之前
but when in my experience a layered
但是根据我的经验
architecture without more restrictions
没有更多限制的架构
than just the layer layer one can call
不仅可以调用一层
layer two layer two can call layer three
第二层第二层可以调用第三层
this this is the only restriction in a
这是唯一的限制
layered architecture if you don't put
分层架构，如果您不放
any more restrictions on it
对此有更多限制
it's very prone to design flaws that
很容易出现设计缺陷
creep in over time so keep keep this
随着时间的流逝，请保持这一状态
disclaimer in mind if while I'm bashing
如果我正在扑打，请记住免责声明
on layered architecture so a good
在分层架构上，所以很好
layered architecture is a good
分层架构是一个很好的
architecture but one thing I have
建筑，但我有一件事
observed in and a lot of projects in in
在中观察到很多项目
my experience that we're doing actually
我实际所做的经验
database driven design a lot in our
数据库驱动的设计在我们很多
layered architecture what does that mean
分层架构是什么意思
it means that we have a service layer
这意味着我们有一个服务层
the in regice or a business domain layer
regice或业务领域层
which which is in red in the empty
里面是红色的
slides and we have a persistence layer
幻灯片，我们有一个持久层
which is
这是
and in the domain layer we have our
在域层，我们有
services stateless services that do
无状态服务
something that implemented business
实施业务的东西
logic that implement the main logic and
实现主要逻辑的逻辑
in our persistence layer we usually have
在我们的持久层中，通常
an entity class which is for example a
实体类，例如
JPA entity a repository which is the
JPA实体是一个存储库
spring data JP a repository perhaps and
spring data JP一个存储库，也许
this makes this this couples the domain
这使得这耦合域
logic in our services very much to the
我们服务中的逻辑对
database why is that it's because the
数据库为什么是因为
entity has all the the JPA annotations
实体具有所有JPA批注
and stuff like that and in our service
诸如此类的东西以及我们的服务
if we're using the JPA entity directly
如果我们直接使用JPA实体
we have to take care of things like lazy
我们必须照顾懒惰
loading and everything that that can go
加载以及可以进行的所有操作
wrong with using JPA III like JP a very
使用像JP这样的JPA III是非常错误的
much I use it I like to use it very much
我经常使用它我非常喜欢使用它
but in my experience there are we're
但根据我的经验，
actually solving problems in our domain
实际解决我们领域中的问题
layer that should be solved in the
应在
persistence layer so these couples are
持久层，所以这些夫妇是
the main logic to the database or at
数据库或数据库的主要逻辑
least to the to the database to the
至少到数据库到
persistence layer before the database
数据库之前的持久层
and usually we're starting in a setup
通常我们是从安装开始
like this when we're developing a
当我们开发一个
certain use case we're starting at the
某些用例，我们从
bottom layer we're starting creating and
底层，我们开始创建
we're starting by creating an entity
我们从创建一个实体开始
creating a repository creating the
创建一个存储库
database table the database structure
数据库表数据库结构
and only then we're going to the domain
只有这样我们才能进入域
layer and build our application logic
层并构建我们的应用程序逻辑
when it should be the other way around
什么时候应该相反
we should build the business logic first
我们应该先建立业务逻辑
and then care about the data that the
然后关心那些
database and persistence there because
数据库和持久性在那里，因为
the business logic is the more important
业务逻辑更重要
code
码
the next thing about layered
关于分层的下一件事
architecture is that we're usually
架构是我们通常
having this service layer this domain
在这个域中拥有此服务层
layer and if we have certain classes
层，如果我们有某些类
that are used through our multiple
通过我们的倍数使用
layers we just push them to the bottom
层，我们只是将它们推到底部
most layer because everyone can access
因为每个人都可以访问
them so we have a utility classes and
他们，所以我们有一个实用程序类，
perhaps other classes that are needed
也许需要其他班级
everywhere that that should be accessed
应该访问的每个地方
everywhere we just push them down to the
到处我们都将它们推到
lower most layer so every other layer
最下层，所以每隔一层
above it can can use it
上面可以使用它
this makes boundary the boundaries we
这使边界成为我们的边界
have they're easily blurred if you don't
如果不这样做，它们是否容易变得模糊
if you don't have the discipline or if
如果你没有纪律，或者
you don't have something in place that
你没有合适的东西
that catches it so there is no no real
抓住了它，所以没有真正的
boundary if you don't if you don't if
边界，如果不，如果不，
you don't especially build it into your
您不会特别将其内置到您的
architecture next thing is layered
体系结构的下一步是分层
architecture allows shortcuts like layer
体系结构允许像图层一样的快捷方式
bridging we were accessing the
桥接我们正在访问
persistence layer from our web layer for
Web层的持久层
example which is not bad per se but if
这个例子本身还不错，但是如果
we do this
我们这样做
then the tests are going to be a little
然后测试会有点
harder at least if we were doing unit
至少如果我们在做单位的话更难
tests so for the tests and in our
测试，以便进行测试
controller here we would have to mock
控制器在这里，我们将不得不嘲笑
the business layer away and we would
业务层消失了，我们将
especially have to mock away
尤其要嘲笑
repository so we're having a lot of
仓库，所以我们有很多
mocks if someone new comes to the team
嘲笑是否有新人加入团队
and sees the the test code you might get
并看到您可能获得的测试代码
confused tests are getting harder we're
困惑的测试越来越难了
have we have to mock more we have to
我们必须要模拟更多吗
mock different different layers
模拟不同的不同层
different technologies is it's going to
不同的技术将
be a little harder than if we just have
比我们只有一点点困难
to mock away only one there next
嘲笑下一个
important thing I have observed in a lot
我已经观察到很多重要的事情
of projects is that the functionality
项目的功能是
we're building the use cases we're
我们正在建立用例
building in our application are actually
建立在我们的应用程序中实际上
hidden somewhere we have a service
隐藏在我们提供服务的地方
which is a business service or domain
这是业务服务或域
service or whatever and it's doing a lot
服务或其他什么，它正在做很多事情
of different use cases so for example we
不同的用例，所以例如
have a service that is concerned about
有关心的服务
orders so to create an order to update
订单，以便创建要更新的订单
in order to I don't know place an order
为了我不知道下订单
whatever and this service does
随便，这项服务
everything for orders and everything
一切为了订单和一切
that that that's around the entity or
围绕实体的
around the order entity and you don't
围绕订单实体，您不会
really if you're looking for a certain
真的，如果您正在寻找某个
use case in the codebase you know that
您知道代码库中的用例
it's somewhere in this this order
在这个顺序的某个地方
service but you don't have you have to
服务，但您不必
search through the service to actually
通过服务搜索到实际
find it so this is makes makes use cases
找到它，这就是使用例
usually makes use cases hard to find if
通常很难找到用例
we have these broad services that are
我们提供以下广泛的服务
spanned across multiple use cases and it
跨越多个用例，它
also makes makes hard makes it hard to
也让努力变得困难
work in parallel on the same feature so
在同一功能上并行工作，因此
if two developers are developing are
如果两个开发人员正在开发
working on this on the same or similar
在相同或相似的位置上工作
feature they have to they both have to
他们必须具备的功能
work in this service and might have
从事这项服务，可能有
merged conflicts and other problems so
合并冲突等问题
what's the cure instead of layers we
有什么治疗方法，而不是分层
just do circles so we just wrap the
只是做圈，所以我们只包装
layers around each other and everything
彼此和所有事物的层次
that's better
那更好
I'm not done yet there's something
我还没完成呢
coming in okay so this is what Uncle Bob
好吧，这就是鲍伯叔叔
Robert Martin called clean architecture
罗伯特·马丁称清洁建筑
I'm going into a little more detail
我要详细一点
later but first let's look at solid
稍后，但首先让我们看一下固体
solid principles everyone knows them
每个人都知道的坚实原则
right you can if you're if you're
对，如果你是，就可以
getting woken up in the middle of the
在中间醒来
night you can say what s oli D is right
晚上你可以说oli D是对的
who can do that oh come on I know you
谁能做到这一点哦，我知道你
can okay I'm not going are going to ask
可以吗，我不会去问
you now I'm just going to open this up
你现在我要打开这个
so a single responsibility principle
因此，单一责任原则
open-closed principle Liskov
开闭原理
substitution principle interface
替代原理接口
segregation principle dependency
隔离原则依赖性
inversion principle we're only going to
反演原理，我们只会
look at two here which which I think are
看两个我认为是的
the most important ones and which
最重要的
motivate the architecture style that I'm
激发我的建筑风格
going to introduce so let's look first
要介绍一下，让我们先来看
at the dependency inversion principle
在依赖倒置原则
what does that mean obviously it means
这显然意味着什么
that we can invert dependencies in some
我们可以在某些情况下反转依赖关系
way it means that this is our on the
这意味着这是我们的
left side is our database driven design
左侧是我们的数据库驱动设计
now we have the service we have the
现在我们有服务，我们有
entity and repository and the service
实体和存储库以及服务
has a dependency on the on the
依赖于
persistence layer so we're bound we're
持久层，所以我们必须
coupled to the to the database through
通过耦合到数据库
the entity if we apply the dependency
实体，如果我们应用依赖项
inversion principle we turn this
反转原理，我们把这个
dependency around so that no longer the
周围的依赖，这样就不再
the domain layer no longer has a
域层不再具有
dependency to the persistence layer but
依赖于持久层，但是
the other way around this is on the
另一种解决方法是
right side we see we have yeah okay I
右边，我们看到我们有，是的，我
also replaced service with use case here
在这里也用用例替换了服务
but that doesn't matter it means on the
但这没关系，这意味着
right side we're using dependency
右边我们正在使用依赖
inversion which means we have moved the
倒置意味着我们已经移动了
entity up into the domain layer so that
实体进入域层，以便
our domain entity that this
我们的域实体
is actually now a domain entity no
现在实际上是域实体
longer a JPA or hibernate or whatever
使JPA或休眠状态或更长的时间更长
entity and in the domain layer we added
实体，并且在域层中我们添加了
an interface which I called repository
我称为存储库的接口
here but which doesn't necessarily have
在这里，但不一定
to be named like that and the
被这样命名
persistence layer simply implements this
持久层只是实现了这一点
repository interface with whatever
仓库接口与任何
technology is sensible in the project
技术在项目中是明智的
JPA spring data JDBC whatever so what
JPA spring数据JDBC不管怎样
this means is we can choose the
这意味着我们可以选择
dependent the direction of any
取决于任何方向
codependency as long as we have control
只要我们有控制权
over the code if we have a dependency to
代码，如果我们有一个依赖
some third-party framework third-party
一些第三方框架
library obviously we cannot change the
图书馆显然我们不能改变
dependency because we can't change the
依赖，因为我们无法更改
coach so what does that mean on an
教练，这对一个人意味着什么
architecture level and this is where the
体系结构级别，这就是
clean architecture ID comes into play
干净的建筑ID发挥作用
clean architecture as a as a buzzword is
干净的体系结构作为流行语是
not that young it's been around I don't
不那么年轻，它就在我身边
know for a long ten years or so I'm not
知道了十年左右，所以我不是
really sure but Robert Martin has
真的很确定，但是罗伯特·马丁有
recently published the book clean
最近出版的清洁书
architecture about this which explains
关于这个的架构说明
this architecture style but it's very
这种建筑风格，但是非常
generic but I'm going to this is the
通用，但我要去的是
only slide about it actually so I'm
实际上只是滑行所以我
going to not go into the details here
不会在这里详细介绍
but go over the main main facts so what
但是要回顾主要的主要事实
have we here we have in the middle our
我们在这里吗我们在中间吗
domain layer and there are layers around
域层，周围有层
that and the the main rule is that
那主要规则是
dependencies only may point in words so
依赖只能指向单词，所以
for example the blue circle we have the
例如我们有一个蓝色圆圈
UI code the code for the UI or the code
UI代码UI的代码或代码
for accessing the database it may acts
用于访问数据库，它可能会起作用
as the green layer and the green layer
作为绿色层和绿色层
may access the red layer something like
可能会像这样访问红色层
that we have applied the dependency
我们已经应用了依赖
inversion principle to actually allow
实际允许的反演原理
this change of dependency yes and this
这种依赖关系的变化是的，这
is actually it we have the domain logic
其实我们有领域逻辑
actually in the core and everything on
实际上是核心，一切都在
the outside is just a detail so if you
外面只是一个细节，所以如果你
believe Uncle Bob the database and the
相信Bob叔叔的数据库和
web are actually only detailed to our
网络实际上只是向我们详细
application the important stuff is the
应用程序的重要内容是
red stuff in the middle I see that a
在中间的红色东西，我看到一个
little more pragmatic I think it's
多一点务实，我认为这是
pretty important that we have a web
我们拥有一个网络非常重要
layer and then we have a database layer
层，然后我们有一个数据库层
because otherwise the data just gets
因为否则数据只会
lost but what it means is that we can
迷失了，但这意味着我们可以
actually change the database later on
稍后实际更改数据库
and exchange it by I don't know storing
和我不知道存储交换
storing files on a hard drive or
将文件存储在硬盘上或
something like that so this is
像这样的东西是
dependency inversion depend we inverted
依赖倒置依赖我们倒置
the dependencies our domain layer is no
我们的领域层没有依赖关系
longer dependent on a persistence layer
不再依赖持久层
because we turned the dependency around
因为我们改变了依赖
by introducing an interface and
通过引入一个界面和
implementing this from the outside the
从外部实施
next solid principle I want to talk
我想谈的下一个坚实原则
about is single responsibility the
关于单一责任
single responsibility principle who
单一责任原则
knows what it what it means yeah just I
知道这意味着什么，是的，只是我
can see you anyway just tell me what
仍然可以看到你告诉我什么
what does it mean single responsibility
单一责任是什么意思
here you're cheating yes I was expecting
在这里，你在作弊，是我所期待的
something like a class or module should
类似类或模块的东西
do only one thing but what you said is
只做一件事，但你说的是
completely right a class or module
完全正确的类或模块
should actually only have one reason to
实际上应该只有一个理由
change so this is a common
变化，所以这是常见的
misinterpretation of the single
对单身的误解
responsibility principle that it only
只负责的原则
should do one thing while actually it
实际上应该做一件事
should only have one reason to change
应该只有一个改变的理由
it's a slight difference and it's not
这是细微的差别，不是
not so big a difference but but a
差别不大，但是
meaningful difference because if a
有意义的差异，因为如果
certain module or class there's one
某些模块或类有一个
thing but it has multiple reasons to
东西，但是有多种原因
change because there are different
变化，因为有不同
requirements that that that have that
具有那个的要求
that produce a change in in this modular
在这个模块中产生了变化
class then it's going to change all the
类，那么它将改变所有
time while if a certain modular class
某个模块化课程的时间
only has one reason to change it's only
只有一个改变的理由
going to be changed for this one reason
将因为这个原因而被改变
and this makes the code base just more
这使得代码库更加丰富
stable so and instead of module I put
所以稳定，而不是我把模块
the word module here instead of module
这里的单词模块而不是模块
you can read class package component
您可以阅读课程包组件
whatever element architecture or code
任何元素架构或代码
element you want so what does single
您想要的元素，那么什么单
responsibilities mean on a on a macro
责任是宏观上的意思
level on an architectural level if we
如果我们在建筑水平上
look at the layered architecture our
看看我们的分层架构
business layer or our domain layer has
业务层或我们的域层具有
one reason to change that it shouldn't
改变它不应该的一个理由
have and that's the persistence layer
有，那就是持久层
below if we change something in the
下面，如果我们在
persistence layer in the blue layer and
蓝色层的持久层和
the bottommost layer there is a certain
最底层有一定的
possibility that we have to change
我们必须改变的可能性
things in the business layer too because
业务层中的事情也是因为
the dependency shows points downwards so
依赖性显示点向下，所以
changes in persistence may affect
持久性的变化可能会影响
business code which we don't really want
我们不想要的商业代码
in this clean architecture circle
在这个干净的建筑圈里
circular style when we applied the
当我们应用圆形样式
dependency inversion principle this is
依赖性反转原理这是
no longer the case
不再如此
because the dependencies point towards
因为依赖性指向
our business layer and if something on
我们的业务层，如果有的话
the outer layers changes the business
外层改变业务
layer doesn't have to change so this
层不必更改，所以这
makes the business code more stable this
使业务代码更稳定
means single reason to change single
意味着改变单一原因
responsibility on a high level on a
高层的责任
macro on an architecture level and this
在体系结构级别上的宏
means we're we're free to do everything
意味着我们可以自由地做任何事情
we we see fit everything that we think
我们认为适合我们认为的一切
is good in our domain layer we can do
在我们可以做到的领域层中是很好的
everything without even having to think
一切都无需思考
about persistence effect persistence
关于持久性效果持久性
problems lazy loading stuff like that
问题懒惰加载这样的东西
and I go so far and say that only a
我走到很远，说只有一个
domain centric architecture where which
以领域为中心的架构在哪
has the domain layer in the middle of it
中间有一个领域层
independence is pointing toward the
独立指向
domain layer allows domain driven design
域层允许域驱动设计
because only then we can design and we
因为只有这样我们才能设计
can design freely without having to
可以自由设计而无需
think about certain technology issues
考虑某些技术问题
only goes so far but the gist is that
只走了这么远，但要旨是
this is this is true what does it mean
这是真的，这意味着什么
on a micro level on a class level single
在微观水平上，在单班水平上
responsibility in our layer architecture
我们层架构中的责任
we we often have the case that we have
我们经常遇到这样的情况
these broad services I talked about
我谈到的这些广泛的服务
earlier and we have multiple actors
早些时候，我们有多个演员
using this service so for example if
使用此服务，例如
this is an order service providing use
这是提供使用的订单服务
cases around orders placing orders
下订单案例
whatever and we have three different
随便，我们有三个不同
three different user roles that actually
实际上是三个不同的用户角色
use this service use use cases in the
使用该服务中的用例
service we have three actors that use
服务我们有三个参与者
the service so if one of these actors at
因此，如果这些参与者之一
one of these user roles requires a
这些用户角色之一需要
change to the to the application we have
更改为我们拥有的应用程序
to change this service and we have to
改变这项服务，我们必须
test everything else that in it again
再次测试其中的所有其他内容
even if the other two actors
即使其他两个演员
are not actually don't think that
其实并不认为
anything has changed so what can we do
一切都变了，我们该怎么办
here we can split our service up into
在这里我们可以将我们的服务分为
use cases actual classes that are named
用例命名的实际类
XY z-- that use case and each service or
XY z-用例和每个服务或
use case whatever you call it is
用例无论您叫什么
responsible for one actor for one user
对一个用户负责一个演员
role and if you take this to the extreme
角色，如果您将其发挥到极致
every of these classes actually only
这些课程实际上只是
responsible for one use case so and this
因此，一个用例负责
brings me to the next architecture style
带我进入下一个建筑风格
which is hexagons so we're talking a lot
这是六边形，所以我们在谈论很多
of we're talking about a lot of shapes
我们谈论的是很多形状
today I think a hexagon is more sexy
今天我觉得六角形更性感
than a circle because it has these edges
比圆，因为它有这些边缘
but that's just personal meaning what
但这只是个人含义
does it mean if we drill into an
这是否意味着如果我们钻进一个
hexagonal architecture this is my
六角形的建筑，这是我的
interpretation of an a hexagonal
六角形的解释
architecture it looks like this we have
我们看起来像这样的建筑
a hexagon obviously six sides six
六边形六边六
corners and within the hexagon we have
角和六边形内
our domain layer or domain code use
我们的域层或域代码使用
cases entities on the edge of our
案例实体在我们的边缘
hexagon of our application core we have
我们应用核心的六边形
ports on the left side we have input
我们在左侧的端口输入
ports and on the right side we have
端口，在右侧，
output ports input meaning we provide an
输出端口输入意味着我们提供了
interface we provide an API to outward
接口，我们提供向外的API
let's call them adapters to outward code
我们称它们为向外代码的适配器
that wants to call our application logic
想调用我们的应用程序逻辑
and on the right side the output ports
在右侧的输出端口
provides functionality for for example
提供功能，例如
persistence we call our our application
持久性我们称之为应用程序
core called something else so why is
核心叫别的东西，为什么呢
this a hexagon
这个六角形
I don't really know and I don't think
我真的不知道，我也不认为
mr. Cockburn who branded the the word
先生。冠以“ Cockburn”字样的人
hexagonal architecture I'm think I read
我想我读的六角形建筑
somewhere that he mean men's just it's
他说男人只是在某个地方
because boxes with four corners are
因为有四个角的盒子是
boring and he wanted to show that an
很无聊，他想表明
architecture can actually have more than
架构实际上可以拥有超过
four sides I don't really know what he
我不知道他的四个方面
meant but if you think that six sides
意思是，但如果你认为这六个方面
are too much for you you can just choose
对您来说太多了，您可以选择
any polygon you want for example if the
您想要的任何多边形，例如
customer is says that oh six six sides
顾客说哦，六个六面
are too much for me you can just go with
对我来说太多了，你可以去
a triangular architecture but then you
三角形的建筑，但是你
should be prepared that the customer
应该为顾客做好准备
only wants to pay half for it because it
只想为它付出一半，因为它
only has half the number of sides so be
只有边数的一半，所以
careful with that so actually the
小心一点，所以实际上
hexagon doesn't really mean anything but
六角形实际上并不意味着什么
it looks cool so we will stick with a
看起来很酷，所以我们会坚持
hexagon back to use cases I mentioned
我提到的六角形用例
before that use cases should be that
在那之前，用例应该是
that services should be cut into
服务应该切入
multiple use cases so that each use case
多个用例，以便每个用例
only has a single actor so use cases we
只有一个演员，所以用例我们
should treat use cases as first-class
应将用例视为一流
citizens in our architecture and in a
市民在我们的建筑和
hexagonal architecture this is just much
六角形的建筑
more concrete that in a clean in the
更干净的
clean architecture I am introduced
介绍干净的建筑
earlier if you google the words clean
较早的时候，如果您用谷歌搜索干净
architecture and hexagonal architecture
建筑和六角形建筑
you find very much about the baha'i
你对巴哈伊有很多了解
level concepts but at least if you if
级别的概念，但至少如果
you're looking for clean architecture if
您正在寻找干净的建筑，如果
you're looking for hexagonal
您正在寻找六角形
architecture you even get some code
架构，您甚至可以获得一些代码
examples because the clean architecture
例子，因为干净的架构
there's it's just a concept and
只是一个概念而已
hexagonal architecture is just is an
六角形的建筑只是一个
instance of clean architecture which
清洁建筑的实例
actually puts the concepts to which is
实际上把概念放在
easier to to turn into actual code
更容易变成实际的代码
so what does a use case do a use case
那么用例做什么用例
class implements an input port the input
类实现输入端口的输入
port is just a Java interface then the
端口只是一个Java接口，然后
use case class modifies the domain model
用例类修改域模型
the domain entities in some in some way
领域实体以某种方式
and on the way it might call certain
并在途中可能会
output ports for example to load data
输出端口，例如加载数据
from the database or to send data to the
从数据库或将数据发送到
database or to load data from some other
数据库或从其他数据库加载数据
external system whatever let's have a
外部系统，不管我们拥有
look at the impact of of this this this
看这个这个的影响
style of this architecture file with
此架构文件的样式
with having specific use case classes so
具有特定的用例类，因此
this is a package structure of a little
这是一个小小的包装结构
application without actual use cases can
没有实际用例的应用程序可以
anyone tell what this application does
有人告诉这个应用程序做什么
pardon it records time yes very smart
原谅它记录时间是的，非常聪明
any anybody any other guess well it
任何其他人都猜对了
obviously does some some something with
显然在做一些事情
time so you're completely right you
时间，所以你完全正确
can't tell any more than it records time
除了记录时间，别无所求
so no offense to you I couldn't have
所以对你我没有冒犯
seen it anyway either it does something
反正看到它要么做某事
we have we have a service it does
我们有我们提供的服务
something with with time records but
有时间记录但
what's the time record I don't know what
什么时间记录我不知道
what do we do with these time records I
我们如何处理这些时间记录
don't know if we split it up in use
不知道我们是否分开使用
cases instead we get this anyone tell
情况下，我们得到这个告诉任何人
now what this application does pardon
现在，此应用程序可以做些什么
yes managers time records we can even
是的，经理们甚至可以记录时间
probably go one level deeper we see that
可能更深一层，我们看到
we have multiple use cases we can submit
我们有多个用例，我们可以提交
time records we can approve time records
我们可以批准时间记录
we can reject time records so it's
我们可以拒绝时间记录，所以
actually probably multiple users
实际上可能有多个用户
multiple roles we have a proving use
我们已经证明了多种角色
case which is done by probably another
这种情况可能是由另一个
role so it's probably a time time
角色，所以可能是时候
tracking application where you track
跟踪您跟踪的应用程序
your time and later on you you create
您的时间，以后再创建
invoices from that and track time you
发票并跟踪您的时间
can do this in a layered architecture
可以在分层架构中做到这一点
too so this is certainly a good way to
也是，这当然是一个很好的方法
go but in this in this hexagonal
去，但在这个六角形
architecture this is even more powerful
体系结构，它甚至更强大
because of the dependency inversion and
因为依赖倒置和
we don't have to change use cases
我们不必更改用例
because persistence code changes okay
因为持久性代码可以更改
let's look at some code I promise to
让我们看一下我承诺的一些代码
show some code you can find the code
显示一些代码，您可以找到代码
examples at this link or in the slides
此链接或幻灯片中的示例
can you see it okay so what does code
你可以看到吗，代码是什么
look like so this is just just a
看起来就像这只是一个
disclaimer this is my interpretation
免责声明，这是我的解释
there are certain we we can certainly do
有一定的我们一定可以做到
it in different style this is just one
它以不同的风格只是一个
one template one could use to create
一个可以用来创建的模板
such a hexagonal architecture with or
带有或
without spring I'm going to point out
没有春天，我要指出
the the spring parts on the way
途中的弹簧零件
so this is our we're going to implement
这就是我们要实施的
a use case that is called register book
用例，称为注册簿
use case so the application is about is
用例，因此该应用程序是关于
a book reviewing application so if you
书评申请，因此，如果您
write a book you can upload the book in
写一本书，你可以上传这本书
Mactan or whatever other format and you
Mactan或其他格式，您
can provide it to other people who can
可以提供给其他可以
then review the book and and edit and
然后查看本书并进行编辑和
suggest edits and stuff like that so the
建议编辑和类似的东西，所以
first use case in this applications is
此应用程序的第一个用例是
to register a book so I'm an all
注册一本书，所以我全是
of a book and I want to register my book
一本书，我想注册我的书
there it actually is a simple create use
那里实际上是一个简单的创建用途
case we just create a book but I don't
情况下，我们只是创作一本书，但我没有
call it create book because that's too
称它为创造书，因为那也是
generic
通用的
I call it register book so we should try
我称它为注册书，所以我们应该尝试
to call our use cases with the most with
用最多的调用我们的用例
the best verb possible and create it's
最好的动词并创造它
just too generic so we have this
太普通了，所以我们有这个
register book use case which is an
注册书籍用例
interface this is our input port in the
接口，这是我们在
hexagonal architecture it has a single
六角形的建筑，它只有一个
method currently which is register book
当前的方法是注册簿
which takes a register book command
这需要一个注册簿命令
which contains every all the data that
包含所有的数据
is needed to execute this use case the
需要执行此用例
register book command I put it here in
注册书命令，我把它放在这里
into this interface as well
也进入这个界面
it just has has two fields and a
它只有两个字段和一个
constructor that takes these fields as
将这些字段用作的构造函数
input here's the first question
输入这是第一个问题
about validation I chose to validate the
关于验证，我选择验证
the input on this level so the register
该级别的输入，因此寄存器
book command actually implements and/or
book命令实际上实现和/或
extends a self validating class which
扩展了一个自我验证类
simply does some creates a Java Bean
只是做了一些创建一个Java Bean
validation validator and called the
验证验证器，称为
validations so its results these it
验证，因此其结果
evaluates these bean validation
评估这些Bean验证
annotations so we can only create an
注释，因此我们只能创建一个
command object that is valid in the
在中有效的命令对象
sense that the business logic expects so
感觉到业务逻辑期望如此
the business logic itself can then work
然后，业务逻辑本身可以工作
with these attributes and doesn't have
具有这些属性，并且没有
to do the validation itself there's also
进行验证本身也有
an exception here which I don't know if
我不知道是否有例外
it's a good idea non-unique book title
这是一个好主意非唯一书名
exception perhaps a better way would be
例外，也许更好的方法是
to not use this to not create an
不使用它不创建一个
exception in this case but instead
在这种情况下例外，但是
before calling the register book method
调用注册簿方法之前
to actually check if there is already a
实际检查是否已经有一个
book but that's just a little flavor so
书，但是那只是一点味道
we have this register book use case no
我们有此注册簿用例
spring so far even though there is here
到目前为止，即使有春天
and spring icon so what does actually
和弹簧图标，那么实际上是什么
implement this this interface I called
实现这个我调用的接口
it register book service so it's a
它注册图书服务，所以这是一个
service which which serves only this
仅为此服务的服务
this actual one use case and it
这个实际的用例，它
implements this method and so we're
实现此方法，所以我们
starting when we're starting to
当我们开始
implement this register book method we
实现我们的注册簿方法
just type away and implement our
只需键入并实施我们的
business logic and we find that we need
业务逻辑，我们发现我们需要
an author entity so we just create an
作者实体，所以我们只创建一个
output port which I called find author
我称为查找作者的输出端口
by a deport which only has this one
被只有这一项的驱逐出境
method find author by ID and we're
方法通过ID查找作者，我们
happily coding some more well then we
高兴地编码得更好，然后我们
find okay we need to persist this book
觉得还可以，我们需要坚持这本书
somehow so we create another output port
以某种方式，我们创建了另一个输出端口
which which takes the book and persists
拿书并坚持下去
in the database still very little spring
在数据库中仍然很少的春天
here but we're using Springs at service
在这里，但我们在使用Springs
annotation to declare this service as an
注释以将该服务声明为
as an as a spring bean one thing you
作为Spring bean ，一件事
could do here is if you want to make the
如果您要制作
architecture even more evident in in the
建筑在
code you can create your own annotation
您可以创建自己的注释的代码
and annotate this meta annotate this
并注释此meta注释此
annotation with the add component
带添加组件的注释
annotation annotation and then you
注释注释，然后您
actually know when you look at this that
其实知道当你看着这个
this is a use case spring serves as a
这是一个用例弹簧用作
dependency injection mechanism here to
依赖注入机制在这里
fill these fields I'm using Lombok here
填写这些字段，我在这里使用龙目岛
which create automatically creates a
会自动创建一个
constructor for all required for all
全部所需的构造函数
final attributes and spring
最终属性和春天
automatically injects implementations of
自动注入的实现
these ports so if we have created a test
这些端口，所以如果我们创建了一个测试
before
之前
and we run the test now and without
我们现在就可以进行测试
having implemented the these ports that
已经实现了这些端口
the spring container won't won't fire up
弹簧容器不会起火
and it will tell us there is a port
它会告诉我们有一个港口
missing which is which is pretty cool
错过了那是很酷的
because there's spring checks our
因为有春天检查我们
architecture for us okay so this is the
对我们的体系结构好吧，这就是
business logic very little spring here
这里的业务逻辑很少
the only thing spring does is actually
春天唯一要做的就是
dependency injection that's the way it
依赖注入就是这样
should be so spring is very non-invasive
应该是这样，春天是非常无创的
we can spring spring is in the behind
我们可以春天在后面
the scenes and just does the work behind
场景，然后做后面的工作
the scenes and we don't have to actually
场景，我们不必实际
use any spring code except for perhaps
使用任何春季代码，除了
one or two annotations so this is our
一两个注解，这就是我们的
business code I didn't actually explain
我实际上没有解释的商业代码
the package structure so we have an
包装结构，所以我们有一个
application package structure which with
应用程序包结构与
a port package input ports output ports
一个端口包输入端口输出端口
so these are just the interfaces and we
这些只是接口，我们
have a service package within the
内有一个服务包
application package which has our
具有我们的应用程序包
register book service so now we someone
注册图书服务，所以现在我们有人
have to implement these ports and these
必须实现这些端口
ports are implemented by our persistence
端口由我们的持久性实现
adapter so hexagonal architecture we
适配器，所以我们六角结构
have the core in the middle and on the
在中间和中间有核心
outer layers we have adapters that call
外层，我们有调用的适配器
our core or that are called by us and
我们的核心或被我们称为
here I took again I created a custom
在这里，我再次创建了一个自定义
annotation which you don't have to you
您不需要的注释
can also use this one but it just makes
也可以用这个，但是
it more evident and this implements some
它更明显，这实现了一些
output ports it's in a it's in its own
自己的输出端口
package and every class in this package
包和该包中的每个类
actually is packaged private we don't
实际上是打包的，我们不打包
need to publish it out to the outside of
需要将其发布到外部
this package because spring allows to
这个包装是因为弹簧允许
inject beans into the spring context
将beans注入春天
without them actually being public which
没有他们实际上是公开的
is pretty cool because we don't we can't
很酷，因为我们不能，我们不能
accidentally accidentally call
意外地
persistence code from our business layer
我们业务层的持久性代码
then
然后
so on this is pretty simple code it
所以这是非常简单的代码
takes it takes a book and saves it this
拿一本书并保存下来
is a spring data JDBC repository pretty
是一个Spring数据JDBC存储库
simple stuff yeah one thing about this
简单的东西是这个
book class the book class is in our
读书课读书课在我们的
domain package so this is actually in
域包，所以它实际上在
the in the middle of our of our
在我们中间
hexagonal architecture I don't forget to
我不会忘记的六角形建筑
track your time sure I will
一定要跟踪您的时间
we I chose here to add this ID
我们在这里选择添加此ID
annotation this is an annotation of
注解这是对
spring data spring data JDBC or actually
弹簧数据弹簧数据JDBC或实际上
I think it's not even JDBC it's just
我认为这甚至不是JDBC，而只是
spring data in general so I chose to
春天的数据，所以我选择
just to use the same object in my
只是为了在我的身上使用相同的对象
persistence there as I use in my
像我在我中使用的持久性
business layer this but but the
业务层，但
persistence layer needs this ID
持久层需要此ID
annotation so now I chose to just put it
注解，所以我现在选择只放它
here this is a kind of a shortcut
这是一种捷径
because again in my business code I
因为再次在我的业务代码中
actually don't want to have any
其实不想要任何东西
persistence any dependency to
坚持任何对
persistence code but I think if you're
持久性代码，但我认为如果
starting to build a use case many use
开始建立许多用例
cases start as as a single as a simple
案例始于简单
Crotty use case we create some entity or
克罗蒂用例我们创建一些实体或
something like that we can start with
这样的事情我们可以开始
this so we can add some JPA or spring
这样我们可以添加一些JPA或spring
data annotations to the entity in the
实体中的数据注释
actual in the in the business layer and
实际在业务层中
then we can just pass this entity along
然后我们就可以传递这个实体
to the persistence layer then persisted
到持久层然后持久
in whatever database however once we get
在任何数据库中，但是一旦我们得到
to a point where the use case evolves to
到用例演变为
something more complex and we we start
更复杂的事情，我们开始
we're thinking about oh we're doing some
我们正在考虑哦，我们正在做一些
persistence relevant code here in in the
持久性相关代码在
business layer we can then choose to
业务层，然后我们可以选择
remove this annotation from our domain
从我们的网域中删除此注释
object
宾语
and then just do an introduce a mapping
然后做一个介绍映射
here so here we would map the book to
在这里，所以我们将这本书映射到
some JPA
一些JPA
entity or or we just move it to the
实体，或者我们只是将其移至
database / via plain JDBC so that's
数据库/通过普通的JDBC，所以
that's what I want to bring across we
这就是我想带给我们的
don't actually have to start with this
实际上不必从此开始
very strict boundaries between the
两者之间的界限非常严格
layers we can move we can start without
我们可以移动的层，我们可以开始没有
these mapping steps because that's one
这些映射步骤，因为那是一个
of the main criticisms about hexagonal
关于六角形的主要批评
architecture or clean architecture in
建筑或清洁建筑
general that we have to in each layer we
一般而言，我们必须在每一层中
have our own model and we have to map
有我们自己的模型，我们必须映射
between these models but it we don't
在这些模型之间，但我们没有
necessarily have to do it this way we
一定要这样做
should start to do it this way if we
如果我们应该开始这样做
think we're doing code in the if we're
认为我们在做代码，如果我们
putting code in the business layer that
将代码放在业务层中
has to do with persistence and stuff
与持久性和东西有关
like that so there's also a web adapter
这样，还有一个网络适配器
in the adapter package which is simply a
在适配器包中，它只是一个
rest control which is I'm not going to
休息控制，我不会
details there because it's pretty
那里的细节，因为它很漂亮
straightforward
直截了当
okay so we've seen this we've seen this
好的，所以我们已经看到了
so to sum up what what spring does for
总结一下春天的作用
us in our architecture Spring doesn't
我们在我们的架构中，春天没有
really care about the architecture we're
真正在乎我们的架构
implementing which is a good thing
实施这是一件好事
spring is always in the background has
春天总是在后台
been in the background since day one I
从第一天起我就一直在后台
guess so if we think about architecture
如果我们考虑一下架构，那就猜猜
spring doesn't care we can build any
春天不在乎，我们可以建立任何
architecture with with spring so we
与春天的建筑，所以我们
really have a lot of options of doing
确实有很多选择
things
东西
spring also helps to test isolated parts
弹簧还有助于测试孤立的零件
of our architecture we've seen in the
我们已经在
talk before about the the component
先谈一下组件
scanning and stuff like that but we can
扫描之类的东西，但是我们可以
also do specific java configuration
也做特定的java配置
files that only spin up part of
只旋转一部分的文件
application so that we can test this
应用程序，以便我们可以对此进行测试
part of our application in in isolation
孤立地应用程序的一部分
Oliver drop what Walmart has given a
奥利弗掉下沃尔玛给的东西
talk yesterday about modulus this is one
昨天谈论模数，这是一个
option we can we can also do here and to
选择我们可以，我们也可以在这里和
sum up spring is easily held at arm's
总结弹簧很容易放在手臂上
length so we don't really have to buy
长度，所以我们真的不必购买
into using spring because spring is in
使用弹簧，因为弹簧在
the background ok I'm going to skip the
好的背景，我要跳过
mapping strategies because I've just
映射策略，因为我刚刚
told I've just told you about it that we
告诉我我刚刚告诉过你
can use different mapping strategies we
可以使用不同的映射策略
can do no mapping so the the ports the
不能做任何映射，所以端口
output ports and the persistent setup
输出端口和持久设置
they use the same entity as the domain
他们使用与域相同的实体
layer or we can do something like this
层，或者我们可以做这样的事情
in the front in the in the interface to
在界面的最前面
the web adapter using a command pattern
使用命令模式的Web适配器
which is a more elaborate mapping
这是一个更精细的映射
strategy how can we enforce architecture
策略我们如何执行架构
just really quick we can build multiple
真的很快，我们可以建立多个
jar files separate build artifacts so
jar文件将构建工件分开，因此
that the dependencies are resolved
依赖关系已解决
automatically by maven or Gradle or
由Maven或Gradle自动或
whatever we can use something like Ark
不管我们可以使用方舟之类的东西
unit which is a framework that allows to
单元是一个框架，可以
enforce certain package structures or
实施某些软件包结构或
even more than package structures
甚至比封装结构
actually I'm only using it here to
其实我只是在这里用
enforce package structures package
执行包结构
dependencies actually or we can use the
依赖关系，或者我们可以使用
modulus approach by Olly which he
他的奥利模量法
introduced yesterday I just edit this
昨天介绍的我只是编辑这个
slide after the talk we can use Java
讲完幻灯片我们可以使用Java
modules which will probably work too but
模块也可能会工作，但
I'm used to having a little more time to
我习惯有更多时间
learn new Java stuff so I haven't looked
学习新的Java知识，所以我没有看过
at it yet yeah that's about enforcing
是的，是的，关于执行
the octave which which is important
重要的八度
enforcing the architecture is kind of
加强架构有点
important because if you're not doing
重要，因为如果您不这样做
microservices yes I set microservices
微服务是我设置了微服务
for the first time in this talk which
这是本次演讲中的第一次
which is great if you're not doing
如果你不做那很棒
microservices if you're building the
微服务，如果您正在构建
application in a giant in a monolithic
在巨石中的应用
code base then it's very important to
代码库，这对于
enforce architectural rules because
实施架构规则，因为
otherwise certain design flaws will slip
否则某些设计缺陷会滑倒
in okay to conclude what are the
可以得出什么结论
benefits of a domain centric
以领域为中心的好处
architecture like clean architecture or
像干净的建筑或
hexagonal architecture we have separate
我们有独立的六角形建筑
classes for separate reasons of change
出于不同变化原因的课程
so we don't have this disk up into the
因此我们没有将此磁盘放入
database we can find our use cases
数据库，我们可以找到我们的用例
better because we separate them in in
更好，因为我们将它们分开
certain in different classes we can work
可以在不同的班级工作
in parallel better because we have cut
并行更好，因为我们削减了
things up into more small pieces it's
东西变成更多的小块
easier to test because the dependencies
更容易测试，因为依赖项
are clear and the boundaries are no
是清楚的，没有界限
longer blurred so easily there are
不再模糊所以容易有
certain drawbacks certainly just as I
某些缺点当然与我一样
said there is if you do it if you make
说如果有的话就做
hard boundaries boundaries at building
硬边界
boundaries is expensive just ask Donald
边界很贵，只是问唐纳德
Trump I think he's he has a problem with
特朗普，我认为他是他的一个问题
the boundary currently so we have each
目前的边界，所以我们每个都有
boundary requires if you want to do
边界要求，如果你想做
heart boundaries you have to do a
心脏边界，你必须做一个
mapping and so it might feel that you
映射，因此可能会感觉到您
have to map a lot we have some perceived
必须映射很多，我们有一些感知
redundancy because if we cut the use
冗余，因为如果我们减少使用
cases if we make the use cases separate
我们将用例分开的情况
from each other
彼此
we have to duplicate some things so if
我们必须重复一些事情，所以如果
we change one use case the other one
我们改变一个用例，另一个
won't have to change and we need real
无需更改，我们需要真正的
business logic it's very hard if you
业务逻辑，如果您很难
just do a simple crud application you
只是做一个简单的应用程序
don't need this architecture style so
不需要这种建筑风格
this only really helps if you have real
这只有在您拥有真正的
business logic that you can put into the
您可以放入的业务逻辑
middle of your into the center of your
你的中间到你的中心
architecture then you have the real
建筑，那么你有真正的
value and that's it thanks for your
价值，就是这样，谢谢您
patience I've summarized some of this
我已经总结了一些耐心
and a little more in a little a book
一本书多一点
which you can download under this link
您可以在此链接下下载
thank you for your patience
感谢您的耐心等待
it has been a lot of fun for me
对我来说很有趣
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]